A Guide to the Commissioners of Revenue Reports on Joint Stock Companies 1848 - 1850, bulk 1850
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Commissioners of Revenue reports on joint stock companies paying dividends, 1848 - 1850, bulk 1850
The Library of Virginia
APA 385
.5 cf
Auditor of Public Accounts
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
No acquisition information available.
Biographical Information
In 1850 the auditor of public accounts sent circulars to the local commissioners of revenue asking for the names of joint stock companies paying dividends in their districts. These reports were sent to the auditor in response.
Scope and Content
Contains reports of joint stock companies paying dividends sent to the auditor by district commissioners of revenue. Includes a list of "Tax on Dividends" from 1848, and a copy of the letter that was sent to the commissioners of the revenue throughout the state. A majority of localities reported that no such companies existed in their jurisdiction. Those that did report joint stock companies would list just the company name or go on to include the head of the company and the board of directors. Many companies existed across multiple localities, and are listed several times throughout the reports.
Arrangement
Documents are arranged chronologically, and then alphabetically by locality.
Contents List
- Commissioners of Revenue reports on joint stock companies paying dividends 1848-1850
  - Tax on Dividends, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Commissioners of Revenue reports on joint stock companies paying dividends: Counties, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 2 - 8)
    - Accomack, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Albemarle, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Amherst, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Appomattox, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Augusta, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bath, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bedford, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Berkeley, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Botetourt, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Braxton, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Burke, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Brunswick, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Buckingham, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Cabell, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Campbell, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Caroline, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Charles City, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Charlotte, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Clarke, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Culpeper, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Cumberland, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Dinwiddie, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Fairfax, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Fauquier, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Fluvanna, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Franklin, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Frederick, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Giles, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Gilmer, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Gloucester, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Grayson, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Greenbrier, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Greene, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Halifax, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Hampshire, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Hanover, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Hardy, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Harrison, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Henry, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Highland, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Jackson, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Lee, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Lewis, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Logan, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Loudoun, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Louisa, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Marion, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Marshall, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Mason, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Matthews, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Mecklenburg, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Mercer, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Middlesex, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Monongalia, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Monroe, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Montgomery, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Morgan, 1850 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Nansemond, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Nelson, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - New Kent, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Northampton, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Norfolk, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Ohio, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Orange, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Patrick, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Pittsylvania, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Pocahontas, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Preston, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Prince Edward, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Prince George, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Princess Anne, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Pulaski, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Putnam, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Patrick, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Raleigh, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Randolph, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Rappahannock, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Rockbridge, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Richmond, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Roanoke, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Russell, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Scott, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Shenandoah, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Smyth, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Southampton, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Spotsylvania, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Stafford, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Surry, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Sussex, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Warwick, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Taylor, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Tazewell, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Warren, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Wirt, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Wetzel, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Wythe, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - York, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Commissioners of Revenue reports on joint stock companies paying dividends: Cities, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Fredericksburg, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Lynchburg, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Norfolk City, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Petersburg, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Wheeling, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Williamsburg, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 9)